Samantha Sloan

Broomfield, Colorado 80020 (303) 489-1303 | samantha.sloan31@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/slsloan | www.github.com/slsloan | https://slsloan.github.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Detail-oriented professional with 5+ years of experience and a proven knowledge of customer satisfaction, report building for team efficiency, and in-depth knowledge of the specific software that is used. Passionate individual with an affinity for organization and data management. Looking to utilize my new knowledge from my Full Stack Bootcamp in an environment that will let me focus solely on keeping the data clean.

PROJECTS

Travel Buddy

GITHUB: http://rocky-scrubland-02427.herokuapp.com/

- SUMMARY: For project three we were tasked at building an app using MERN stack. We decided on a travel budgeting app that allowed the user to create a profile that they could add new trips to and allocate funds to specific categories for each individual trip.
- RESPONSIBILITIES: I worked a lot on the back-end (MongoDB database) of the application getting the user profile to authenticate the user information and link the correct trip information to that user. Spent some time on the routes to ensure they worked with the models created in the application so that it would appear correctly on the front end.
- TOOLS / LANGUAGES USED: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, NPM, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Dotenv, Nodemon, Reactjs, React-Router, Materialize Framework, FramerMotion, Chartjs, and Heroku

Fetch! A Dating App for Dogs

GITHUB: http://yoyage-choucroute-01318.herokuapp.com/

- SUMMARY: For project two we were tasked at building an app using the MVC paradigm and our own server-side API. We decided on a dog dating app where you could add new dogs to a database and then view the dog's data on a map generated by the Google Maps API.
- RESPONSIBILITIES: I worked on both the front-end and back-end of the application. On the front-end, I worked to create the forms that were used to fill out the information as well as the card that you could pull up the specific dog information on. For the back-end, I worked on creating the routes, models, schema, and ensuring the back-end data was communicating properly with the front-end information that was being entered in.
- TOOLS / LANGUAGES USED: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, NPM, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, Dotenv, Nodemon, Express-handlebars, Materialize Framework, Heroku, JAWSDB, Google Maps, FileStack

Eat-Da-Burger

GITHUB: https://github.com/slsloan/burger | https://quiet-garden-01878.herokuapp.com/

- SUMMARY: In this assignment, I created a burger logger with MySQL, Node, Express, Handlebars and a homemade ORM (yum!). I used the MVC design pattern; use Node and MySQL to query and route data in my app, and Handlebars to generate my HTML.
- RESPONSIBILITIES: I created this whole application from scratch working with both the front-end and back-end of the application. I created and set up the database using SQL so that I could connect a ORM that would allow us to perform the CRUD (create, read, update, and delete) functions for the application.
- TOOLS / LANGUAGES USED: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, AJAX, NPM, Nodejs, Bootstrap, Sequelize, MySQL, Heroku, JAWSDB

EXPERIENCE

Gusto, Denver, Colorado - Outbound Sales Representative

MARCH 2019 - PRESENT

- Exceeds metric expectation in number of dials, upgrades, and add-ons for the quarterly expectations.
- Developed new procedures to ensure efficiency for our team.
- Improved reporting systems to help clean up the data to reflect accurate information for our team
- Utilizes the Sandler Sales Methodology to work with prospects on deciding whether or not they should move forward with Gusto as their Payroll, HR, and Benefits platform.
- Works cross-functionally with other teams to ensure that customer satisfaction is high.

Global Healthcare Exchange (GHX), Louisville, Colorado - Customer Support Analyst II

JULY 2018 - FEBRUARY 2019

- Identify, research, and resolve customer issues, questions, and concerns in a timely manner.
- Defined problems, collected data, and established facts to draw valid conclusions.
- Provide customers with product and service information.
- Complete call logs and reports.
- Used Salesforce to create and manage cases on customer issues, questions, or concerns

Hyland Hills Parks & Recreation District, Westminster, Colorado - Manager/Group Sales

AUGUST 2011 - AUGUST 2018

- Scheduling group events by phone and email, entering in a point-of-sale system.
- Event planning, setup, and hosting for private corporate and customer parties and customer appreciation events.
- Developed and enforced safety standards and procedures for food quality and sanitation purposes.
- Assisted Operation Manager with balancing, identifying and reconciling daily transactions.
- Payroll system timesheet entry and reporting.
- Recruited, interviewed, hired and trained employees on new procedures and requirements.
- Supervised up to 15 team members.
- Producer, cinematographer, and editor of training videos.

EDUCATION

Denver University, Denver, Colorado - Certificate in Full-Stack Development

MARCH 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2020

Colorado State University, Fort Collins, Colorado - Bachelor of Science - Hospitality Management

AUGUST 2013 - MAY 2017

Minor in Business Administration

Dean's List Fall 2015-Spring 2017